<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SiddharthVipul</title>
    <link>http://vsiddhar.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SiddharthVipul</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vsiddhar.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 30 Release Party Event Report</title>
      <link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/fedora_30_release_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/fedora_30_release_party/</guid>
      <description>Some Contest Celebrating Fedora Release Party is now a custom in Bangalore. This time, although late, we organized it in Red Hat Banglaore Engineering office. We were expecting 30 people to attend the party and we received a fairly good response with ~25 people on and off. Some came for SilverBlue, some to install Fedora 30 and some wanted to know more about the 31 changesets. It was a rather successful event considering it was a working day AND RootConf was at the same $day:time on a different part of city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flock2018</title>
      <link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/flock_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/flock_blog/</guid>
      <description>WOW! What an experience it was to meet all the people I have been knowing through IRC..faceless people with random nick that has nothing to do with their name.. but brilliant minds who make a very open, inclusive, welcoming and a powerful project possible!
 This was my first Flock and It has been the best conference/event I have ever attended.
 Unlike other conferences where there are a lot of people presenting their own project and are distributed in groups, everyone in the Flock was connected to a single string, Fedora!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>websiteInfo</title>
      <link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/websiteinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/websiteinfo/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss vsiddhar.me I have been suggested multiple time to manage a blog, share my stories, events and ideas, but as being a &amp;lsquo;Pro&amp;rsquo; procrastinator, I haven&amp;rsquo;t run from my responsibilities and thus, haven&amp;rsquo;t done the right thing! Sadly, this changes now. I have decided to manage this colorless website (Hugo+Coder, as it requires ~no effort). If I am alive and in right sense, I will be putting at least one post every week month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact &amp; Social Network accounts</title>
      <link>http://vsiddhar.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vsiddhar.me/contact/</guid>
      <description> IRC Nick:  irc.freenode.net: siddharthvipul irc.devel.redhat.com: siddharthvipul Channels where you can find me: #centos-ci, #fedora-devel, #fedora-apps &amp;hellip;  Telegram: siddharthvipul Email: [spam protection, base64 encoded]  c2lkZGhhcnRodmlwdWwxCg==@gmail.com (personal) dmlwdWwK@redhat.com (work)  Time Zone: UTC + 5:30 FAS Account:siddharthvipul1 Social networks:  Twitter: siddharthvipul GitHub: siddharthvipul LinkedIn: siddharthvipul Facebook: siddharthvipul   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vipul is</title>
      <link>http://vsiddhar.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vsiddhar.me/about/</guid>
      <description>  He/His/Him part of CI Infrastructure team in Community Platform Engineering @ Red Hat developing and administering CentOS CI while trying to contribute to some Fedora Apps ambassador @ Fedora Project FOSS enthusiast &amp;amp; evangelist a self declared developer and a command line hero  Contact &amp;amp; Social Network accounts  Contact Page  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>