<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on SiddharthVipul</title>
		<link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on SiddharthVipul</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="http://vsiddhar.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>GCI mentor&#39;s summit</title>
			<link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/gci_mentors_summit/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/gci_mentors_summit/</guid>
			<description>Context Google Code-in is a contest to introduce pre-university students (ages 13-17) to open source software development. Since 2010, 8,108 students from 107 countries have completed over 40,100 open source tasks Because Google Code-in is often the first experience many students have with open source, the contest is designed to make it easy for students to jump right in. I was one of the mentors in this first time for Fedora program.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h1 id="context">Context</h1>

<p>Google Code-in is a contest to introduce pre-university students (ages 13-17)
to open source software development. Since 2010, 8,108 students from 107
countries have completed over 40,100 open source tasks Because Google Code-in
is often the first experience many students have with
open source, the contest is designed to make it easy for students to jump right
in.
I was one of the mentors in this first time for Fedora program. We had 125 students participating in Fedora and the top 3 students completed 26, 24 and 22 tasks each.</p>

<h1 id="mentors">Mentors</h1>

<p>Very active and helpful group of mentors helped the students whenever required.
We were 5 mentors</p>

<ul>
<li>Abhishek</li>
<li><a href="http://www.anujjain.xyz/">Anuj</a></li>
<li><a href="https://badges.fedoraproject.org/user/algogator">Algogator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://badges.fedoraproject.org/user/amitosh">Amitosh</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:siddharhvipul1">/me</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Jonatoni">Jonatoni</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:sumantrom">Sumantrom</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Our winners:</p>

<ul>
<li>Alex Margii</li>
<li>EchoDuck</li>
</ul>

<p>Every year Google invites Grand-Prize winner and their parents, and a mentor to it&rsquo;s
headquarters in San Francisco, California for 4 days trip. This report covers
activities and other things that happened there.</p>

<h3 id="day-00-reception">Day 00 (Reception)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Meeting the mentees at the hotel (4:30)</li>
<li>Opening reception at 5:00pm at the Google San Francisco office for all attendees.</li>
<li>Welcome (snacks and appreciating everyone&rsquo;s efforts)</li>
<li>Swag giveaway

<ul>
<li>Students got Pixel 3xl phones and a bag full with a jacket and 2 T-shirts.</li>
<li>Mentors got the bag with a Jacket and 2 T-shirts as well</li>
<li>A lot of GCI and GSoC stickers</li>
<li>Pens/Pins/&hellip;</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Dinner</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="day-01-full-day-at-google-headquarters-in-mountain-view">Day 01 (Full Day at Google headquarters in Mountain View.)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Take shuttle to the Google headquarters</li>
<li>See around Googleplex</li>
<li>Visit Google Merch store (students were provided $150 and mentors $75 to
purchase merchandise of their choice)</li>
<li>Students met Google Employees from their home country and had lunch with them</li>
<li>Talks by Google employees

<ul>
<li>Recruiting -  Lauren Alpizar</li>
<li>Android OS: Ally Sillins</li>
<li>Cloud:  Ryan Matsumoto</li>
<li>Chrome OS - Grant Grundler</li>
<li>Google Assistant - Daniel Myers</li>
<li>Google TensorFlow - Paige Bailey</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Dinner and then back to the hotel</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="day-10-fun-day-in-san-francisco">Day 10 (Fun Day in San Francisco)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Cable car around the city and see

<ul>
<li>Twin Peaks, San Francisco</li>
<li>Golden gate park</li>
<li>Golden gate bridge (also, walked across it)</li>
<li>Dinner on a Yacht</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="day-11-closing-reception-in-google-sf-office">Day 11 (Closing reception in Google SF office)</h3>

<ul>
<li>Breakfast</li>
<li>Award ceremony (to grand prize winners)</li>
<li>Presentation (by mentors and winners - 4 minutes each)</li>
<li>Lunch</li>
<li>Interview recording</li>
<li>lunch and closing reception at Google San Francisco office. Events end no later than 3:00pm.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Fedora 30 Release Party Event Report</title>
			<link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/fedora_30_release_party/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/fedora_30_release_party/</guid>
			<description>Context Celebrating Fedora Release Party is now a custom in Bangalore. This time, although late, we organized it in Red Hat Banglaore Engineering office. We were expecting 30 people to attend the party and we received a fairly good response with ~25 people on and off. Some came for SilverBlue, some to install Fedora 30 and some wanted to know more about the 31 changesets. It was a rather successful event considering it was a working day AND RootConf was at the same $day:time on a different part of city.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h1 id="context">Context</h1>

<p>Celebrating Fedora Release Party is now a custom in Bangalore. This time,
although late, we organized it in Red Hat Banglaore Engineering office. We were
expecting 30 people to attend the party and we received a fairly good response
with ~25 people on and off. Some came for SilverBlue, some to install Fedora
30 and some wanted to know more about the 31 changesets. It was a rather
successful event considering it was a working day AND <strong>RootConf</strong> was at the same <code>$day:time</code> on a
different part of city. People love RootConf.</p>

<h1 id="what-happened-in-the-celebration">What happened in the celebration</h1>

<ul>
<li><p>I started the event by discussing <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Fedora_30_talking_points">talking points</a> of Fedora 30.
When I reached changes in security, questions started coming it. Thankfully we
had a Gluster Engineer who works a lot around libcrypt and he was able to drive
the discussion into a very productive one.</p></li>

<li><p><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Sinnykumari">Sinny</a> spoke and showed demo of SilverBlue. We had so many question it
lasted for an hour.</p></li>

<li><p>[Anuj] and I discussed Fedora Summer Coding programs and did an unofficial
call for mentors in case there is something that they wish for Fedora and
want to make it a success by taking it on their own. :P (focus on unofficial)</p></li>
</ul>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Bex">Bex</a> for sending us a good amount of Swag that made the participants
(and me :P) super happy. Followed by swag distribution, we cut the cake (cut by a user who has promised that he will contribute the
package he is facing issues into by doing update testing).
Cake, Swag and cherry on top we had burgers for everyone. It was an wonderful
and a successful event.</p>

<p>Post food and networking, I showed how to test packages to Digganta (The guy
who cut the cake).
We called off the event by 06:00 pm. A good 4 hours of users/contributions
meeting was amazing to see!</p>

<p>Thanks to all the participants, and Red Hat Bangalore site managers to  provide
us the venue and snacks.</p>

<p><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Sumantrom">Sumantro</a> was missed.</p>

<p>A rather short report, now enjoy some pictures <a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/Lnr78rGmLXiqTBzB9">here</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Flock2018</title>
			<link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/flock_blog/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/flock_blog/</guid>
			<description>WOW! What an experience it was to meet all the people I have been knowing through IRC..faceless people with random nick that has nothing to do with their name.. but brilliant minds who make a very open, inclusive, welcoming and a powerful project possible!
 This was my first Flock and It has been the best conference/event I have ever attended.
 Unlike other conferences where there are a lot of people presenting their own project and are distributed in groups, everyone in the Flock was connected to a single string, Fedora!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h1 id="wow">WOW!</h1>

<p>What an experience it was to meet all the people I have been knowing
through IRC..faceless people with random nick that has nothing to do with
their name.. but brilliant minds who make a very open, inclusive, welcoming
and a powerful project possible!</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This was my first Flock and It has been the best conference/event I have ever attended.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unlike other conferences where there are a lot of people presenting their own
project and are distributed in groups, everyone in the Flock was connected to a
single string, Fedora!</p>

<p>read for a brief summary of the event.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="where">Where?</h3>

<p>Radisson Blu,
<strong>Radebeul - Dresden</strong> | Germany</p>

<h3 id="when">When?</h3>

<p>During the hottest time in whole Europe (which is not very bad)</p>

<p><strong>August 7th</strong> to <strong>August 11th</strong></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="a-bit-about-the-talks-and-presentations">A bit about the talks and presentations</h2>

<p>Keynote &lsquo;State of Fedora (Objectives &amp; Editions)&rsquo;
started at 9&rsquo;o clock in which <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Mattdm">Matthew
Miller</a>, <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Bex">Brian
Exelbierd</a>,
<a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Sgallagh">Stephen Gallagher</a>, <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Dustymabe">Dusty Mabe</a>,
<a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Pbrobinson">Peter Robinson</a> and <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Langdon">Langdon White</a>
presented
 * stats, successes, ups, and downs of the Fedora Project.
 * About Flock and it&rsquo;s value.
 * About SIGs
 * where as a community we stand and the areas we need to improve.</p>

<p>Combined, a very insightful and informative presentation.</p>

<p>I tried to attend as many talks/workshops as possible still keeping some time
in hand to meet those amazing people in person and discuss a few ideas (or at
least share a handshake).
Every talk was full of discussion. The Attendees
were not just there to listen and take notes, but to provide their input which
I have never seen anywhere else.
So many planning meetings, SIGs gathering and a lot of snacks during the tea
break (thanks ARM for sponsoring it) made it a perfect event.</p>

<p><strong>My schedule</strong>: <a href="https://flock2018.sched.com/siddharthvipul1">https://flock2018.sched.com/siddharthvipul1</a></p>

<h2 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h2>

<p>Flock didn&rsquo;t just involved talks and knowledge sharing, but also candies.
Credit goes to Justin for organizing the International candy swap event.
Everyone brought what they thought authentic and local from their country
including some weird ones to have fun. well,
the weird credit goes to Göran and me. TBH what I took (Pulse candy) was
not really weird, but like Indians, not everyone likes spices in their candy.
Oh wait, this doesn&rsquo;t mean that the candy that Göran brought wasn&rsquo;t weird&hellip; It
was scary! But that&rsquo;s what made the event even more memorable. We had a lot of
fun making people try it and waiting for their reaction.</p>

<p>Amazing <a href="https://twitter.com/DomiBula">Dominika Bula</a> had organised a scavenzer hunt for us which was
designed to make us explore the city center .</p>

<p>Then we went to Roller Coaster Restaurant which was different, thus awesome!
Other fun things like game night, karaoke event, and eating everyday out with
others, going for a walk in a biiiig group, laughing and enjoying (/me cries
and gets nostalgic)</p>

<p>It was an experience that no one can say no to. I am definfitly loolking
forward to attend more of such events.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Thank you Fedora for sponsoring my trip :)</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>websiteInfo</title>
			<link>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/websiteinfo/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://vsiddhar.me/posts/websiteinfo/</guid>
			<description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss vsiddhar.me I have been suggested multiple time to manage a blog, share my stories, events and ideas, but as being a &amp;lsquo;Pro&amp;rsquo; procrastinator, I haven&amp;rsquo;t run from my responsibilities and thus, haven&amp;rsquo;t done the right thing! Sadly, this changes now. I have decided to manage this colorless website (Hugo+Coder, as it requires ~no effort). If I am alive and in right sense, I will be putting at least one post every week month.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h1 id="let-s-discuss-vsiddhar-me">Let&rsquo;s discuss vsiddhar.me</h1>

<p>I have been suggested multiple time to manage a blog, share my stories, events
and ideas, but as being a &lsquo;Pro&rsquo; procrastinator, I haven&rsquo;t run from my
responsibilities and thus, haven&rsquo;t done the right thing! Sadly, this changes now.
I have decided to manage this colorless website (Hugo+Coder, as it requires ~no
effort). If I am alive and in right sense, I will be putting at least one post
every <s>week</s> month.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a small/slow target but for now let&rsquo;s not promise the mountain.
Ideally, I should have migrated my previous blogs, but they are full of color
and also don&rsquo;t make a lot of sense. I have recently (very recently) joined
Fedora Core Engineering (Platform Team) and will be working on CentOS CI, Fedora CI and a bit of
other stuff which I haven&rsquo;t figured out yet.</p>

<p>Most probably this will be updates of my work, few exciting news or small
reads/interesting knowledge sharing platform.</p>

<p>So, keep in touch, I might add some way of notifying people (no promises) or I
might just keep it as my diary (open).</p>

<p>A formal ending with a formal Thank you!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
